AJAY SALUNKE

Phone 9529075303 @salunkeajju007@gmail.com

Pune, Maharashtra

I have 1.6+ years of Experience as a Digital Marketer. Want To Work In A Growth Oriented Organization Where I Can Integrate My Digital Marketing skills in The IT Industry Specially to Excel in the Field Of Digital Marketing. Seeking to utilize marketing background, superb writing skills, and familiarity with Email Marketing and campaign strategy. Familiars with E-commerce platform(Amazon and Flipkart)

EXPERIENCE

E-Mail MARKETING SPECIALIST

Nov.2022-Dec.2023

Machintel System Pvt. Ltd.

Pune

- Handling all over Operation Campaigns Delivery of Client requirement with E-mail marketing.
- Create email marketing campaigns to promote product or service.
- Analyzed email performance metrics and implemented A/B testing strategies resulting in a 30% increase in overall campaign effectiveness.
- Create landing pages and POC's with the help of automated software.
- Ensure marketing message is conveyed clearly and delivered properly to prospect.
- Ensure prompt and accurate communication with targeted audience via email to minimize unsubcribes
- Responsible for quality downloads. Download are the source of revenue and hence it is important to ensure maximum downloads each week
- Identify target audience and grow our email list.
- Implements Email automation strategies, resulting in a 30% increase in overall campaigns effectiveness and a 15% increase in conversion.
- Managed email list segmentation and targeting, resulting in a 40% increase in email engagement and 20% increase in convertion.
- Tools Benchmark, Elastic, Mail jet & Send in Blue.

DIGITAL MARKETING EXECUTIVE

Aug 2021 - Feb 2022(Internship)

Agrostar - (U Link Agritech Pvt.Ltd.)

Pune

CarrollisanAI-drivenmarketingtoolforindividualandsmallbusinesses.Carrollapplets you manage G market your social media accounts.

- Ahrefs, Moz Pro, SEMrush, Google Analytics, Google Search Console, Microsoft Excel.
- Content planning and strategy, with competitor and target audience analysis.
- Copywriting and SEO editing -Strong critical thinking, time management and collaboration skills.
- Social Media Marketing and Data Analysis.
- Website and Keyword Analysis.
- On page- Off Page SEO, SEO Copywriting, Search Engine Guideline knowledge.
- Performed competitor analysis.
- Monitored site traffic, back links and ad performance
- Internal and external link building

EDUCATION

B.Sc. Agriculture

2014 - 2020

K. k. Wagh College of Agriculture, Nashik (University- MPKV, Rahuri)

Percentage: 65.10%

CERTIFICATES

Digital Marketing; Premium School of Digital Marketing,

Pune (2021)

SKILLS

Email marketing A/B Testing **Email Automation Drip Campaigns** SEO TOOLS SITE ANALYSIS WORDPRESS

LANGUAGES

Hindi

Native

English

Intermediate

INDUSTRYEXPERTISE

Customer segmentation and targeting

Knowledge of google analytics

Knowledge of A/b testing and Automation.

STRENGTHS

Problem-Solving.

Fast Learner

Goal oriented